

UX Designer & Researcher

jamesdavidmoffet.com jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com jamesdavidmoffet

about

As a designer and researcher, I am obsessed with understanding the human mechanisms by which technology can deliver us into an alternative future. As a researcher, I have learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of research and management techniques that help me to redirect the internal inertia of established organizations and to find room to apply systems-level, user-centered thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

education

2016 - 2018

Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

SKIIS

Design Research
UI/UX Design
Data Science
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering
Public Speaking
Project Management
Product Design

work experience

OutVote.io

2017 - 2018 Cambridge, MA, USA Director of User Experience
 In 2017, Outvote acquired my civtech
 startup COMM!T, growing to a team of
 five. I direct an agile team of designers,
 coders and researchers to ensure that
 our product that meets the needs of our
 10 enterprise clients and 1000 users.

Independent Consulting

2016-2018 Cambridge, MA, USA

- UXD/UXR Consultant

Collaborated with GoINVO on the MA SNAP web application redesign.
Consulted for City of Boston on FOIA process redesign. Designed open source citizen analytics apps for Cambridge.

MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

- Research Manager

Led a team of 12 researchers, designers and devs conducting field/remote user research on 1,200 grassroots organizing groups. Designed, built and deployed a collaborative mapping tool to help orgs discover each other and connect.

Fulbright Fellow

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU

Lecturer and Researcher

Lectured on design at CEU and piloted OpenLab public design workshops, mentoring UXR, interface design and service prototyping for public projects.

SEIU

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA

Senior UX and Product Manager

Built a user-centered design and engineering team from the ground up, replacing 20-plus-yr-old software products handling all billing and member data. Increased net revenue by 10%, while reducing billing errors by 90%.